Guide to the Norman Forer Files on the Mack Trucks, Inc. (Plainfield, NJ) Relocation Dispute WAG.279
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Norman Forer Files on the Mack Trucks, Inc. (Plainfield, NJ) Relocation Dispute
1955-1964
1961-1962
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Forer, Norman
WAG.279
1 Linear Feet in 1 box
Mack Trucks, Inc. relocated its Plainfield, New Jersey, plant to Hagerstown, Maryland, in 1961. The United Auto Workers negotiated a new agreement with Mack Trucks that was not supported by all the members of the Plainfield local. A court case (Lawrence Giordano et al. v. Mack Trucks, Inc.) was brought in the U.S. District Court District of New Jersey by a small group of plant workers who had formed a group called "Mack Workers Committee for Vested Rights." This collection contains court documents, correspondence, newspaper clippings and other materials that relate to the relocation and legal dispute.
Historical/Biographical Note
On October 31, 1961, the Mack Truck Company shut down its engine and transmission manufacturing plant at Plainfield, New Jersey, and moved its operations to Hagerstown, Maryland. Lengthy negotiations between Mack Trucks, Inc. and UAW representatives had culminated in a new "Shop Separation, Pension and Transfer Agreement." A small group of plant workers (members of UAW, Local 343) were dissatisfied with aspects of the agreement, contending that Mack had ignored "vested rights" of union members obtained through prior contracts. These employees established a group -- Mack Workers Committee for Vested Rights -- and filed suit against the company seeking a restraining order to halt further hiring in Hagerstown and asking monetary damages.
Lawrence Giordano was Chairman of the Committee and Norman Forer, its Secretary.
On March 19, 1962, the US District Court, District of New Jersey, issued an opinion dismissing the complaint and ruling that the plaintiffs were bound by the separation agreement of their UAW union and the defendant Mack Trucks, Inc.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains Normal Forer's papers relating to the dispute surrounding the relocation of a Plainfield, NJ Mack Truck plant to Hagerstown MD. Court documents (Lawrence Giordano et al. v. Mack Trucks, Inc.), newspaper clippings and correspondence describe the actions of Mack Trucks, Inc., leading up to the relocation, their dealings with workers and the union, and the case brought by the Mack Workers Committee for Vested Rights. Also included are committee minutes, copies of several union agreements and a number of fliers, announcements and other material associated with the relocation. In addition, there is documentation of an appeal made by Lawrence Giordano and other members of UAW Local 343 to the international union protesting the manner of the vote on the Shop Separation and Transfer Agreement in October 1961. The appeal was denied. Also of interest is a detailed study of the relocation dispute and how it affected Mack workers -- "The Mack Case: A Study in Unemployment."
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically within one series:
Missing Title
Series I: Mack Truck Plant Relocation Dispute, 1955-1964.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Norman Forer in 1996. The accession number 1996.008 is associated with this gift.
Clippings (information artifacts); Notes.; Minutes (administrative records); Fliers (printed matter); Legal documents.; Correspondence.; Collective labor agreements.; United Automobile Workers. Local 343 (Plainfield, NJ); Forer, Norman; Mack Trucks, Inc.; International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America; Forer, Norman
- Series I: Mack Truck Plant Relocation Dispute, 1955-1963.
  - Agreements, 1958, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agreements, 1961, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Court Documents: Giardano, Lawrence, et al. v. Mack Trucks, Inc., 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Court Documents: Giardano v. Mack Trucks, Jan 1962-Feb 1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Court Documents: Giardano v. Mack Trucks, Mar 1962-Apr 1962, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Court Documents: UAW, Local 343 v. Mack Trucks, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The Mack Case: A Study in Unemployment": Dorsey, John W., [1964] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes: Mack Workers Committee for Vested Rights, Dec 2, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notes and Drafts, 1961, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Personal Documents: Norman Forer, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - International Union, United Automobile, Aircraft & Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW) Appeals Committee Hearing: Giordano, Lawrence, et al. v. Local 343, UAW, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Various Forms, Receipts, Fliers, Announcements and Related Items, 1961-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)